A Guide to the Michael Collins Papers, 1907-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- SERIES XI. HONORS AND MEMORABILIA, 1961-1989
  - Plaques
    - Tuskegee Airmen honorary life membership, November 12 1981 (Box-folder 26-4)
    - Air Force Systems Command, February 1982 (Box-folder 26-5)
    - USS Hornet, July 24 1969 (Box-folder 26-6)
    - Jimmy Doolittle Fellow (Aerospace Education Foundation of the Air Force Association), 1984 (Box-folder 26-7)
    - Jimmy Doolittle Fellow (Aerospace Education Foundation of the Air Force Association), 1989 (Box-folder 26-8)
    - Fiji Police (Box-folder 26-9)
    - "Taken from the eagle's nest: the real reason for 21 days of quarantine" (Box-folder 26-10)
    - Order of the Right Stuff, January 26 1982 (Box-folder 26-11)
    - Gemini Launch Vehicle Division, 6555th Aerospace Test Wing (Box-folder 26-12)
    - "Mike 'Lead Finger' Collins [from the] Gemini X Backup Crew," c. 1966 (Box-folder 27-1)
    - Robert H. Goddard Memorial Trophy, March 18 1970 (Box-folder 27-2)
    - Apollo XI Lunar Module, c. 1969 (Box-folder 27-3)
    - Collins family coat of arms (Box-folder 27-4)
    - T-38 Talon checkout - Edwards Air Force Base, December 6 1961 (Box-folder 27-5)
    - Reproduction of plaque left on lunar surface, July 1969 (Box-folder 27-6)
    - Wooden Apollo 11 insignia - carved by Anneli Bonn and presented by Jack Webb Corp. (Box-folder 28-1)
    - Ceramic piece with profiles of Aldrin, Armstrong and Collins and the names of those involved in the space program - by Edmond Amateis, 1969 (Box-folder 28-2)
    - USAF 25th Anniversary and "Comfort Silver" Awards banquet, 1969 (Box-folder 28-3)
    - Society of Experimental Test Pilots awards banquet, September 27 1969 (Box-folder 28-4)
    - Gemini sunscreen plate, c. 1966 (Box-folder 29-1)
    - USS Guadalcanal- Gemini 10 recovery ship (Box-folder 28-5)
    - Air Force Association's Gill Robb Wilson Award, 1976 (Box-folder 28-6)
  - Memorabilia
    - Photo album commemorating Apollo 11 crew's trip to Germany, October1969 (Box-folder 29-2)
    - Pilot's clipboard with topographical map of Edwards Air Force Base area (Box-folder 29-3)
    - Flight test performance reduction computer (Box-folder 29-4)
    - Academic regalia (yellow and black) (Box-folder 29-5)
    - 16mm film with Collins family scenes (Box-folder 29-6)
    - Commemorative Soviet space medallions (Box-folder 29-7)
    - Assorted memorabilia, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 29-8)
      - Apollo 11 launch invitation, 1969
      - "Voices from the Moon" sound disc (33 1/3 rpm), c. 1969
      - Apollo 11 cartoon, c. 1969
      - Voyager press kit and commemorative button, 1980
      - Original fabric from Kitty Hawk "Wright Flyer"
      - Autographed photos of foreign dignitaries and NASA administrators
      - Apollo 8 Commemorative Medallion (Box-folder 38-1)
  - Medals
    - City of New York seal, August 13 1969 (Box-folder 30-1)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom, August 13 1969 (Box-folder 30-2)
    - Pere Marquette Discovery Award, November 8 1969 (Box-folder 30-3)
    - Belgian medal (Box-folder 30-4)
    - French medal (Box-folder 30-5)
    - Ordem da Solidariedade (origin unknown) (Box-folder 30-6)
    - Thai medal (Box-folder 30-7)
    - Texas Medal of Honor (Box-folder 30-8)
    - Brazilian medals, [2 items] (Box-folder 31-1)
    - Distinguished Flying Cross (Box-folder 31-2)
    - Eagle scout medal (presented by the Boy Scouts of Japan) (Box-folder 31-3)
    - Italian medal (Box-folder 31-4)
    - Orden Jugoslovenske Zevezde Sa Lentom (Order of the Yugoslav Star) (Box-folder 31-5)
    - Distinguished Service Medal (Box-folder 32-1)
    - Japanese Order of Culture (Box-folder 32-2)
    - NASA Distinguished Service Medal (Box-folder 32-3)
    - NASA Exceptional Service Medal (Box-folder 32-4)
    - Korean Order of the Mugungwha (Rose Azalea) (Box-folder 33-1)
  - Oversize Honors and memorabilia (Folder 1)
    - National Aeronautic Association certificate of record, 1966
    - National Moon Walk Day proclamation, July 20 1969
      (signed by Richard Nixon)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom certificate, August 13 1969
    - Assistant secretary of state appointment, December 15 1969
    - Federation Aeronautique Internationale diplome de record, 1969
    - NASA Group Achievement Award, April 2 1973
    - Smithsonian Institution certificate of appreciation, January 27 1980
    - United States Air Force certificate of appreciation to Patricia Collins, February 4 1982
    - Flag flown aboard space shuttle Columbia (from NASA), 1982
    - Flags flown aboard space shuttle Challenger (from American Institute of Aeroanutics), [February 1984]
    - Air Force Reserve certificate of appreciation
    - Apollo translunar / transearth plotting chart, June 23 1969
    - Photo of first lunar landing, July 20 1969
    - Apollo 11 emblem on fabric, c.1969, [3 copies]
    - Soviet poster commemorating lunar landing, [1969?]
    - Lindbergh Awards Dinner poster, May 21 1986
    - Italian lunar map